Omar Rezk

647-983-6093 | omar.rizk6@gmail.com

Summary

I am a Web Developer with a passion for creating web applications and interaction design projects. My journey is constantly evolving through experience I have gained from working on impactful projects, developing efficient solutions and adding to my skill set through continuous education and learning and staying up-to-date with the latest industry technologies.

Work Experience

Dec 2024 - Present Junior Frontend Developer — Brite

- Developed a modular and interactive time picker component in Angular, leveraging core fundamentals such as data binding, event handling, and component-based architecture.
- Designed a responsive UI with SCSS theming, hover effects, and PrimeIcons, ensuring seamless time selection with AM/PM toggle and real-time formatting.
- Created a responsive and interactive sidebar navigation component optimizing UI with scss animations, SVG icons, and smooth transitions, ensuring scalability, performance, and consistent theming.
- Developed a dynamic announcement component, enabling users to create and manage team or company-wide announcements.
- Implemented adaptive UI logic to modify component behavior when multiple announcements exist, created a modal popup to display announcements in latest to oldest order, utilizing Angular's component interaction and state management for real-time updates.

Aug 2020 - Aug 2024 Account Manager/Technical Specialist — Ghost Kitchens Brands

- Served as the point of contact for partners, customers and internal/external stakeholders ensuring issue management, quality control and omnichannel goals are communicated and met.
- Generated an analysis model for sales and performance of all store locations to produce data visualization for operational strategies, revenue goals/KPIs and forecasting and reported to the management team.
- In charge of optimizing and updating web content and overall user experience to increase traffic and sales on delivery platforms such as UberEats, DoorDash, Grubhub and SkiptheDishes.
- Created marketing material in collaboration with the delivery platforms creative team which included brochures, catalogs, photoshoots, campaigns and production assets
- In charge of planning and supporting new store openings through briefing and onboarding for staff at the locations, providing materials and resources leading to successful grand openings of various locations.

Oct 2023 - Oct 2024 Junior Frontend Developer — Glamic

- Developed and maintained responsive web applications using React, HTML, CSS, and JavaScript, resulting in an increase in user engagement and profile completion rates.
- Designed and implemented reusable components, including a dynamic alert system, improving user experience and reducing transactional errors.
- Collaborated with back-end developers to integrate front-end applications with server-side logic and RESTful APIs.
- Applied responsive design principles to create interfaces that enhance user accessibility and functionality across devices.
- Created a toggle feature for portfolio and bio options, utilizing the useState hook for state management and enhancing profile personalization and presentation. Improved user profile customization.

Feb 2019 - April 2023 Graphic Designer/Co-founder — CreativeToo Incorporated

- Managed a diverse portfolio of small and medium-sized business clients across industries, ensuring tailored solutions to meet each organization's unique needs.
- Collaborated with marketing to design & produce graphics using content management systems for various digital & print materials, including brochures, flyers, postcards and social media posts & graphics.
- Designed digital and direct marketing campaigns as well as created brand identities and strategies that resulted in an increase of ROI for multiple clients.
- Managed all social media channels increasing the online presence, which led in the development and execution of demand generation campaigns including ads, email and social media.
- Designed and outlined brand identity including logos, typography, color palettes, shapes and social media graphics.

Education and Certifications

June 2019 **Toronto Metropolitan University**

Bachelors in Graphic Communication Management

Aug 2022 Codesmith

JavaScript & CS prep

April 2023 BrainStation

Diploma, Software Engineering

Sept 2023 Udemy

React Native: Mobile App Development (CLI)

Skills

- HTML5/CSS
- SCSS
- JavaScript
- React.js
- React-Native
- Express.js
- Angular

Oct 2023 BrainStation

Certification, Python

Sept 2024 Coursera

Front-End and Web Development

Oct 2024 Coursera

Google Cybersecurity Professional Certificates

Dec 2024 Frontend Master

Angular 17+ Fundamentals

- Azure DevOps
- RESTful APIs
- Python
- MySQL
- Adobe Creative Suite
- Github
- Data Analytics